<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Santiago&#39;s SDS 348 Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Santiago&#39;s SDS 348 Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working in Python and R with Reticulate</title>
      <link>/blog/working-with-python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/working-with-python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union library(tidyr) library(reticulate) use_python(&amp;quot;/usr/local/bin/python3&amp;quot;) Tidying in R After spending quite a bit of time tidying in R this semester, I prefer tidying in R but still prefer to do analysis more programatically.
iris2 &amp;lt;- iris %&amp;gt;% select(Species) %&amp;gt;% pull()  Interpreting in Python Here I am using Python to do a basic demo of intepretation in Python</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For Project 2: “Modeling, Testing, and Predicting”, I am continuing with my diversity research theme from Project 1: “Exploratory Data Analysis”. The dataset I selected from Kaggle has demographics for 25 Silicon Valley tech companies of various sizes (ranging from 100 professionals to 36,0000). The dataset has categorical variables like company (name), gender (male, female), and job category (e.g. professional, executive, service, etc). There is one numeric variable for the count of people by ethnicity and job category by gender but I plan to tidy the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>| Diversity Across the Fortune 500  
| SDS 348 w/ Dr. Woodward, March 2020  
| R. Santiago Moreno, rsm2785
</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Data Set Attributions Both of my datasets were acquired from Kaggle.
My Fortune 500 Diversity dataset was acquired from: https://www.kaggle.com/fortune-inc/f500-diversity, uploaded by user Fortune
My general Fortune 500 dataset was acquired from: https://www.kaggle.com/vineetjaiswal/fortune500-2017, uploaded by user Vineet
 Introduction I chose two datasets from Kaggle on the Fortune 500 companies from 2017. One data set is generic information on the Fortune 500 with numerical and categorical variables such as Fortune 500 rank, company name, website, sector (as in industry), HQ location, CEO, revenues, profits, and other financial data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>